Register to The E.Y. Harburg Collection
Yale University Music Library
- Writings, 1929-1968; Series I; 20 boxes
  - Writings: Lyrics, Libretti, and Scores
    - Darling of the Day (N.Y. opening: George Abbott Theatre, 1968 Jan 27; music & lyrics by Jule Styne & E.Y. Harburg)
      - "Married Alive" (Toronto production, 1967 Dec 4-16)
        - Notes & suggestions made during rehearsals & tryouts (Box 17, Folder 134)
          Dictated notes, handwritten in pencil -- [1967 Nov] -- 6 pages
          Dictated notes, handwritten by James Clayton, in pencil -- [1967 Nov] -- 16 pages
          Holograph notes, in pencil -- [1967 Dec] -- 19 pages
          Holograph notes, in ink, from Toronto & Boston tryouts -- [1967 Dec-1968 Jan] -- 52 pages
    - Unproduced Musicals
      - "April in Paris" or "The Fatal Fascination" (Box 18, Folder 135)
        (Written for Universal Pictures, 1935) [E.Y. Harburg note: "Film was never produced due to studio's financial difficulties during 1935."]
        Typed treatment for screenplay, carbon, with holograph additions -- 16 pages
        Detailed screen treatment, 1st typed draft, 1935 Feb 5, 2 carbon copies -- 33 pages each
        "The Fatal Fascination" Typed outline for screenplay (registered with Screen-writer's Guild, 1939), signed carbon copy -- 16 pages
      - "The Ziegfeld Follies" (Box 18, Folder 136)
        (Written for MGM, 1939)
        [E.Y. Harburg note: In 1939, while working for MGM, I presented the following new form of revue for pictures. It was too new for them although they did consider it."]
        Sample scene, typed, 2 carbon copies, 1939 Jul 10 -- 3 pages each
        Detailed story treatment, typed, carbon copy 1939 Jul 21 -- 18 pages
      - "The Red Mill" or "The Flying Dutchman" (Box 18, Folder 137)
        (Written for MGM, 1941)
        Story idea by E.Y. Harburg, typed, 1941 Apr 1 -- 2 pages
        Retyped copy ["for Edward Hogan"], carbon copy, 1941 Apr 11 -- 4 pages
        Outline of screen treatment by E.Y. Harburg & Fred Saidy, typed, carbon copy, 1941 Apr 9 -- 10 pages
        Complete screenplay by Saidy & Robert Thoeren, typed, carbon copy, 1941 May 16 -- 63 pages
        Revised screenplay by [E.Y. Harburg &] Saidy, typed, carbon copy, 1941 May 10 -- 77 pages
        Detailed treatment by Charles Lederer, typed, carbon copy, 1941 Sep 20 -- 47 pages
      - "Music or Else" or "Caesar Blows the Horn", [mid-1940?] (Box 18, Folder 138)
        Screen treatment by E.Y. Harburg & Bernard Schubert
        Typed, carbon with holograph corrections -- 16 pages
      - "Huckleberry Finn" (Box 18, Folder 139)
        [for MGM, c. 1950?]
      - "Nellie Bly" (Box 18, Folder 140)
        [planned for MGM or IBM children's cartoon, possibly also for T.V. series; mid-1950s?]
        Research material: "They Called Her the Amazing Nellie Bly," Good Housekeeping magazine [no date] -- 24 pages
      - "The Blacksmith" ["The Village Blacksmith"], [no date] (Box 18, Folder 141)
        Detailed scene outline, handwritten, author unidentified -- 5 pages
      - "Arabian Nights", [no date] (Box 18, Folder 141)
        Story synopsis by E.Y. Harburg, typed, carbon copy with holograph corrections -- 4 pages
      - "Ghost Goes West" [no date; a musical treatment of a c. 1936 London pictures film] (Box 18, Folder 141)
        Holograph notes, in pencil & ink, photocopy [fragments]
      - [Unidentified], [no date] (Box 18, Folder 141)
        Holograph story notes, in pencil -- 4 pages
      - ["Informer"?], [no date] (Box 18, Folder 141)
        Holograph story notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 10 pages
    - Unpublished, Undated Individual Songs
      - "I'll Follow Your Smile" (Box 18, Folder 142)
        (E.Y. Harburg note: "tune by Jerome Kern, never used")
      - "Jimmy Was a Gent" (Box 18, Folder 142)
        (E.Y. Harburg note: "for Radio Music Hall staged by Minelli [sic], 1934")
        Typed lyrics with holograph corrections -- 1.5 pages
      - ["Love Is a Wooden Nickel"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft notes in pencil -- 1 page
      - "Just Walking and Talking" (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft lyrics, in ink -- 4 pages
      - ["Looks Like the End of a Beautiful Friendship"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft notes, in ink & pencil -- 7 pages
      - ["Out in Malibu"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - ["Some Rain Must Fall"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - ["Tarzan"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - ["Take Advantage of Me"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft lyrics, in pencil -- 3 pages
      - ["There's a Sweet Wind Blowing My Way"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft lyrics, in pencil -- 10 pages
      - ["When Autumn Comes My Way"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - ["You Gotta Believe"] (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft notes & lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 6 pages
      - Miscellaneous unidentified lyrics (Box 18, Folder 142)
        Holograph draft notes, in pencil -- 5 pages
  - Writings: Verse
    - Rhymes for the Irreverent [book of verse]
      (Grossman Publishers, N.Y., 1965)
      - Holograph draft manuscript in ink & pencil, 82 pages (Box 19, Folder 143)
      - Holograph draft manuscript in ink & pencil, 104 pages (Box 19, Folder 144)
      - Holograph manuscript in ink & pencil, 74 pages (Box 19, Folder 145)
        [on verso pages of Joshua Logan's script, "Blue Star" 1961 May 31]
      - Typed manuscript, 72 pages (Box 19, Folder 146)
      - Jacket notes by Fred Saidy, typed, photocopy, 2 pages (Box 19, Folder 147)
      - Typed draft verse, carbon copies, & holograph verse in ink & pencil, 10 pages (Box 19, Folder 147)
      - Review, published excerpts, newspaper clippings (Box 19, Folder 148)
      - Published book, autographed, 1968 Oct; 96 pages (Box 19, Folder 149)
    - Published Verse
      - "The Wanderlust," Cap & Bell, City College of New York magazine, 1917 (p. 202), 1 page (Box 20, Folder 150)
      - Light verse, typed, carbon copies [E.Y. Harburg note: "Light verse written during school years - some sold to magazines - most printed in F.P.A. (Adams), columns in New York World & Herald Tribune"] (Box 20, Folder 150)
        "You Will Become a Victim of Hasheesh of the Divine Afflatus" -- 1 page
        "Possible Thoughts of One Whose Wife Has Left His Bed and Board" -- 1 page
        "To...." -- 1 page
        "Sunday Newspaper" -- 1 page
        "Sunday Newspaper" [different poem] -- 1 page
        "Spring...1927 (To Some Bachelor Friends)" -- 1 page
        "Master of Hearts '28" -- 1 page
        "To Margie" -- 1 page
        "Definition" -- 1 page
        "Maturity" -- 2 copies, 1 page each
        "Ballade of Belief" -- 1 page
        "Hope" -- 2 copies, 1 page each
        "Telegraph Poles" -- 2 copies, 1 page each
        "The Spirit of Transportation" -- 1 page
        "A Philosophical Ballad of Female Hypocrisy" -- 1 page
        "Cupid's Boomerang" -- 1 page
        "The Eternal Urge" -- 1 page
        "Spring N'Yawk 1926" -- 1 page
        "The Vernal Urge" -- 1 page
        "The Fox to a Very Sour Grape" -- 1 page
        "Verse for a Grade Crossing" -- 1 page
        "Fair As a Star" -- 2 copies, 1 page each
        "If He Had Written in 1899" -- 1 page
        "Triolet" -- 1 page
        "To Alice (On the California Limited)" -- 1 page
        "Folly Song of 1926" -- 1 page
        "A xms Query" -- 1 page
        "Handicap" -- 1 page
        "Classified" -- 1 page
        "We Can Learn from Birds and Bees" -- 1 page
        "To Edlaine [sic]" (February 1929) -- 1 page
        "French Forms for Collection Departments" -- 1 page
        "Cafeteriosis" -- 1 page
        "Newspaper Dreams" -- 1 page
        "A Birthday Gift" -- 1 page
        "Why Wee Ones Stretch of Morning" -- 1 page
        "All This in a Lifetime" [title crossed out] -- 1 page
        "Reward of the Virtuous Dimple" -- 1 page
        "Consider the Robin" -- 1 page
        "Love Crushed to Earth" -- 1 page
        "Life" -- 1 page
        "The Needle in the Haystack" -- 2 copies, 1 page each
        "Manhattan Fog" -- 1 page
        "Horace on Rivington St." -- 1 page
    - Miscellaneous Verse [unpublished]
      - "Dear Lola" (letter in verse) (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Typed, carbon copy -- 2 pages
      - "Love Will Find a Loophole" [E.Y. Harburg note: "Wedding song for Attorney Prinzmetal of MGM"] (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Typed, 2 carbon copies -- 2 pages each
      - "Romantic Logic" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Typed, carbon copy -- 1 page
      - "To a Belated Love" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Typed, carbon copy with holograph corrections -- 1 page
      - "To Ernest on Discovering His Hands" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Holograph draft in pencil -- 1 page
        Holograph in ink, signed -- 1 page
      - ["To Olive"] (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Holograph draft, in ink -- 1.5 pages
      - "Time" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Holograph fragment, in ink -- 1 page
      - "The Prostitute" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Holograph draft, in ink -- 3 pages
      - "To a Credit Grabbing Producer--Joe Landon" (Box 20, Folder 150)
        Holograph draft, in ink -- 1 page
        [See also Finian's Rainbow correspondence: Box 21, folder 169]
      - ["I'd Never Know a Temple from a Bank"] (Box 20, Folder 150)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - Newspaper Clippings (Box 20, Folder 151)
    - Miscellaneous published light verse, 3 pages [scrapbook]
      - "A Song a Child Could Sing" [Published in At This Point in Rhyme (Crown Publishers, Inc.: New York, 1976)] (Box 20, Folder 151)
        Draft lyrics & notes, in ink & pencil -- 24 pages
        Typed draft, carbon copy with holograph corrections, signed -- 5 pages
  - Writings: Political Songs
    - "Honorable Moon" (Arthur Schwartz-E.Y. Harburg-Ira Gershwin; for United China Relief Fund, 1941) (Box 20, Folder 152)
      Typed draft lyrics with holograph corrections -- 1 page
      Time magazine article including lyrics, 1941 Jul 21
    - "(T'Me Baby) You're News" (Johnny Green-E.Y. Harburg-Ira Gershwin; for Sticks & Stones, a political revue presented by the Motion Picture Artists' committee, 1941-1943?) (Box 20, Folder 152)
      Typed draft, carbon copy -- 1 page
      Program for Sticks & Stones
    - "And Russia Is Her Name" (Kern-E.Y. Harburg; for Tribute to Russia Day, Hollywood Bowl, 1943) (Box 20, Folder 152)
      Souvenir program
      [See Song of Russia, Box 3, Folder 20, for lyrics]
    - "Don't Look Now Mr. Dewey! (But Your Record is Showing)" (E.Y. Harburg-Arthur Schwartz; written in support of F.D.R.'s presidential campaign in 1944), Oversize. (Box 28, Folder 153a)
      Copyist's orchestral score, 22 parts
      Original orchestration by S.M. Morgan, handwritten in pencil, signed -- 14 pages
      Program for Liberal Party rally for F.D.R.-Truman-Wagner, Madison Square Garden 1944 Oct 31, includes lyrics -- 1 page
    - "They Ups to Me" (Music? Written for 1944 F.D.R. campaign) (Box 20, Folder 153)
      Typed lyrics, carbon copy -- 6 pages
    - "Get Out and Vote" (Music? Written for political cartoon, animated by John Hubley, supporting 1944 F.D.R. campaign) (Box 20, Folder 153)
      Typed draft lyrics, carbon copy with holograph additions -- 2 pages
    - "Don't Look Now, Mr. Warren" (Box 20, Folder 153)
      Fragment of melodic line for verse, in pencil
    - "We're in the Same Boat, Brother" (E.Y. Harburg-Earl Robinson; for musical revue presented by Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences, & Professions & The Musicians Congress, 1945 Nov 14) (Box 20, Folder 153)
      Souvenir program, includes lyrics -- 1 page
    - "Freedom Is the Word" (Burton Lane-E.Y. Harburg; written for Freedom Spectacular, closed-circuit T.V. program 1964 Nov 14) (Box 20, Folder 154)
      Holograph draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 19 pages
      Newspaper clipping: article in New York Post, 1964 Apr 27
    - "Black Night at the White House" (Music? Written for Wayne Morse campaign, 1965) (Box 20, Folder 154)
      Holograph lyrics, in ink, 2 copies -- 1 page each
      Holograph draft [earlier version] with margin annotation to "Edlee" -- 1 page
    - "Silent Spring" (Arlen-E.Y. Harburg; anti-nuclear song written for Lena Horne, Carnegie Hall Rally, no date) (Box 20, Folder 154)
      Holograph draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 8 pages
  - Writings: Speeches, Articles, Testimonials
    - ["Chairman's Continuity"] (Script for Paul Robeson, chairman of Madison Square Garden Rally, 1948 Oct 26. Research help from Alan Lomax) (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Typed script, photostatic copy -- 10 pages
    - "The Lyric Writer--Who He? Nobody Knows Him" (Essay in Variety Magazine, 1954 Oct 20) (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Newspaper clipping, photostatic copy -- 1 page
    - "The Legend of Harrywatha" (Verse written for testimonial dinner honoring Harold A. Lifton, C.C.N.Y. Alumni President, 1958 Mar 20) (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Typed verse, carbon copy -- 3 pages
      Testimonial dinner announcement
      Newspaper clipping; New York Times, 1966 Aug 16, obituary notice
    - "The Young Composers" (As told to Gerald C. Gardner), [1961?] (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Typed draft with holograph corrections -- 6 pages
    - "Hindsight Forward" Mock commentary by E.Y. Harburg on avant garde abstract painting (inspired by painting done by Arlen), [1961 Dec] (Box 20, Folder 155)
    - Verse about Barrows Dunham on occasion of his birthday party (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Holograph draft verse, in pencil [1965?] -- 1 page
    - Lecture on Musical Theatre, Columbia University, 1966 Jun (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Holograph notes, in ink -- 6 pages
    - [Speech in Honor of Dr. Jeremiah Stamler, Michigan University, after benefit performance of Finian's Rainbow for Fight Against H.U.A.C., 1967 Apr] (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Typed notes with holograph corrections & 1 photocopy -- 2 pages each
    - Lecture to Drama Students, Columbia University, [1967 Jun] (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Holograph notes in ink -- 5 pages
    - "The Stone Goes Rolling On", 1968 Jan (Box 20, Folder 155)
      For Town Hall Tribute to I.F. Stone; verse written to tune of "Battle Hymn of the Republic"
      Typed lyrics, carbon copy -- 5 pages
      Holograph draft in pencil -- 2 pages
      Newspaper clipping, The Village Voice, 1968 Jan 25 -- 1 page
    - Eulogy for Johnny Burke, 1964 Feb 28 (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Typed draft with holograph revisions -- 2 pages
      Enclosure: handwritten poem by Louis Ginzberg News clipping: American Guild of Authors & Composers Bulletin, 1964 Apr -- 1 page
    - "Birthday Song" for Monthly Review's 15th Anniversary, 1964 May 13; written to the tune of "The Streets of Laredo" (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Holograph draft lyrics, in ink & pencil -- 12 pages
      Monthly Review, Vol 16, no. 2. 1964 Jun (p. 116: full transcript of event)
    - "Annihilation Without Representation" (Statement written for anti-Vietnam War activity) (Box 20, Folder 155)
      News clipping: 3 copies of full-page item from Vineyard Gazette, 1965 Aug 17
    - Speech, Martha's Vineyard Rally for McCarthy for President, 1967 Aug 16 (Box 20, Folder 155)
      Holograph draft, in ink -- 12 pages
      Typed draft, carbon -- 4 pages
    - "Hi, Eduardo!" (Verse written in honor of Dr. Edward [Barsky?], surgeon to Loyalist Spain), [no date]; 1 page (Box 20, Folder 155)
- Harburgiana, 1929-1968; Series II
  When E. Y. Harburg gave his papers to Yale, he labeled the correspondence, publicity, reviews, and memorabilia "Harburgiana." The catch-all term proves, indeed, to be a convenient label for all secondary materials in the collection.
  The substantial amount of correspondence concerning specific musical productions has been listed first, organized chronologically by production, and chronologically within each production.
  General correspondence is listed next and arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent. Harburg kept copies of many of his own letters. These are preceded by "to" in the list. (Most of the original carbon copies were in poor condition and, therefore, have been photocopied.)
  Correspondence regarding Rhymes for the Irreverent, professional affiliations, political and philanthropic activities, and miscellaneous institutional contacts is all arranged chronologically by category.
  Harburg's four large scrapbooks have been preserved separately from the 27 boxes of papers. Due to the poor condition of the originals, photocopies have been preserved in Folders 198-201. In a few cases where the items were of special interest, the originals have been preserved separately in Folder 202, and photocopies mark their places in the scrapbooks.
  Newspaper clippings, publicity, programs, and articles referring to particular musicals are listed under the show titles in chronological order. General writings about Harburg also are listed chronologically.
  Items labeled "Memorabilia" are articles, programs, and invitations that Harburg kept out of professional or personal interest. Except for an occasional reference to him in an article, these materials are not directly related to his work and activities.
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence on Musical Productions
      - Accidentally Yours, [1931] (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - to Starr, Herman, 1942 Jul 1; typed letter (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Starr, Herman, 1942 Jul 3; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - to Starr, Herman, 1942 Jul 6; carbon (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Ballyhoo of 1932
        - Berman, Abraham, 1932 Aug 9; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Howard, Willie & Eugene, 1932 Aug 10; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Americana, 1932
        - Schwartz, Arthur, [1932 Oct ?]; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Morgan, Keith (Chairman, the Committee for the Celebration of the President's Birthday), 1938 Dec 7; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Walk a Little Faster, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Hart, Larry, 1932 Nov 18; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Take a Chance, 1933
        - Starr, Herman, 1945 Jan 24; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Starr, Herman, 1945 Apr 4; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - Life Begins at 8:40, 1934
        - Gershwin, George, 1934 Aug 6; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Kaufman, Harry, 1934 Aug 6; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - MacDonald, Ballard, 1934 Aug 6; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Shulman, Herman & Rose, 1934 Aug 6; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Wynn, Ed, 1934 Aug 6; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Arlen, Harold, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Berman, Abraham, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Hart, Moss, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Lahr, Bert, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - McHugh, Jimmy & Fields, Dorothy, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
        - Schwartz, Arthur, 1934 Aug 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 156)
      - The Show Is On, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Berman, Abraham L., 1936 Mar 12; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Minnelli, Vincente, 1936 Apr 11; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Minnelli, Vincente, 1936 May 11; telegram (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Minnelli, Vincente, 1936 May 16; telegram (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Berman, Abraham L., 1936 May 18; telegram (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Berman, Abraham L., 1936 May 18; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Minnelli, Vincente, 1936 Jul 13; telegram (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Minnelli, Vincente, 1936 Jul 18; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Kaufman, Harry (Shubert Theatre Manager), 1936 Nov 20; [signed contract] (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Hart, Moss, 1937 Oct 27; telegram (Box 21, Folder 157)
        - Harris, Erdman, 1966 Jun 21; autograph letter signed (Box 21, Folder 157)
      - Hooray For What!, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - Secretary to Abraham L. Berman, 1937 May 26; telegram (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - Kaufman, Harry, 1937 May 30; telegram (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - Kaufman, Harry, 1937 Oct 29; telegram (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - Shapiro, Jonas J., 1937 Nov 24; telegram (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - Wynn, Ed, [1937]; telegram (Box 21, Folder 158)
        - to Kaufman, Harry, 1937 Dec 29; carbon & photocopy (Box 21, Folder 158)
      - The Wizard of Oz, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - to Kapp, Jack (Decca Records, Inc.), 1941 Feb 13; signed, carbon (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - Kapp, Jack, 1941 Feb 18; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - to Kapp, Jack, 1941 Mar 4; carbon (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - to Freed, Arthur, 1955 Jun 28; photocopy (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - Allen, Steve, 1959 Apr 23; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - Levinson, Leonard Louis to Scherman, Harry, 1967 Apr 12; carbon (Box 21, Folder 159)
        - Levinson, Leonard Louis to Garland, Judy, 1967 Jul 28; carbon, photocopy (Box 21, Folder 159)
          (Enclosure: lyrics for "Merry Old Land of Oz")
      - Hold On To Your Hats, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 160)
        - Gershwin, Ira, [1940]; news clipping, signed (Box 21, Folder 160)
        - Berman, Abraham L., 1941 Jan 28; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 160)
        - to Dreyfus, Max (Chappell Music Co.), 1943 Jul 16; carbon (Box 21, Folder 160)
        - Sirmay, Albert, 1943 Jul 23; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 160)
      - Babes on Broadway, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Selznick, David O., 1941 Aug 2; telegram (Box 21, Folder 161)
      - Bloomer Girl, 1944
        - Hofenstein, Sam, 1944 Sep 11; telegram (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Kapp, Jack (Decca Records, Inc.), 1945 Jan 5; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Spier, Larry, 1945 Jan 22; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Spier, Larry, 1945 Mar 8; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Meltzer, Herman I., 1945 Jun 28; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - Liebling, William, 1945 Jul 8; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - [?], Lydia, 1945 Sep 28; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
      - Can't Help Singing, 1944
        - Schneider, Leonard W. (Executive Vice-president, Decca), 1953 Mar 20; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 161)
        - to Schneider, Leonard, 1953 Mar 27; carbon, photocopy (Box 21, Folder 161)
      - Blue Holiday, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 162)
        ("Free and Equal Blues")
        - Schuman, Henry, 1944 Oct 23; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Peters, John P. to Davidson, Jo, 1944 Nov 7; carbon (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Reardon, [Re.] Gordon Chilson (to radio station), 1944 Nov 7; postcard (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Williams, C. Fred (to radio station), 1944 Nov 7; postcard (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Davidson, Marion (to radio station), 1944 Nov 8; postcard (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Feibelman, Herbert U. (to Democratic Natational Committee), 1944 Nov 8; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Coward, (Mrs.) Mildred J., 1944 Nov 10; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Wilens, Dorothy (to Democratic National Committee), 1944 Nov 14; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Reardon, Rev. Gordon Chilson, 1944 Nov 15; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Stoertz, Helen E., Fellowship House, Inc., 1944 Dec 6; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - DuBrow, Michael, 1945 Feb 23; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Eliot, Thomas D., Department of Sociology, Northwestern Univ., 1945 May 17; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - to Robinson, Earl, 1947 May 2; carbon, photocopy (Box 21, Folder 162)
        - Seeger, Peter to Meltzer, Herman L., 1947 Jun 1; typed letter signed (Box 21, Folder 162)